<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[FastLED]]></title>
  <link href="http://fastled.io/blog/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://fastled.io/blog/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-13T20:44:53-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://fastled.io/blog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[FastLED]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[FastLED v2.0 Released!]]></title>
    <link href="http://fastled.io/blog/blog/2014/01/13/fastled-2-released-slash/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-13T20:42:49-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://fastled.io/blog/blog/2014/01/13/fastled-2-released-slash</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Dan and I are happy to announce the official Version 2.0 release of the FastLED library (formerly &ldquo;FastSPI_LED2&rdquo;), which is available immediately from <a href="http://fastled.io/releases">http://fastled.io/releases</a> !</p>

<p>A huge THANK YOU goes out to everyone who helped us debug, streamline, and refine V2.  It&rsquo;s taken over a year, but the library is in great shape, and we&rsquo;re ready for it to take on the world. </p>

<p>In addition to releasing the final 2.0 version of the LED library, we&rsquo;ve made a couple of other administrative changes that you should be aware of as well&hellip;</p>

<h2>New Name</h2>

<p>We&rsquo;ve officially changed the library name to &ldquo;FastLED&rdquo;.  This reflects the fact the library supports both SPI and non-SPI-based LEDs, as well as providing a range of LED color and animation support functions.</p>

<h2>New Include File</h2>

<p>The new library folder is called FastLED, and no longer FastSPI_LED2.  This means that you&rsquo;ll want to install the new library, and then update your project code to use #include &lt;FastLED.h> instead of the old #include &lt;FastSPI_LED2.h></p>

<h2>New URL</h2>

<p>We&rsquo;ve set up a new web site for the library: <a href="http://fastled.io/">http://fastled.io/</a>  There are links there to our wiki, code, issue tracker, and to this community.</p>

<h2>New Repository</h2>

<p>We&rsquo;ve moved our code repository from googlecode to github.  Googlecode was getting a old and busted; github is the new hotness.</p>

<h2>What Next?</h2>

<p>What&rsquo;s next is that you start using the new code, and Dan and I catch our breath a little, and then dive into the <em>next</em> version of the library: V2.1, which will be a relatively quick, minor update to add compatibility with a few new microcontroller boards and LED chips.   But first, as I said, we&rsquo;re going to catch our breath.</p>

<p>Thanks again to everyone who&rsquo;s helped make this library what it is today!  Now go forth, and let a thousand pixels bloom.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Post]]></title>
    <link href="http://fastled.io/blog/blog/2014/01/10/first-post/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-10T03:30:47-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://fastled.io/blog/blog/2014/01/10/first-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Poking around with markdown because I have insomnia and want to see this thing up and
running!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
